<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Docs on Statusgraph</title>
    <link>http://moolen.github.io/statusgraph/docs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Docs on Statusgraph</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="http://moolen.github.io/statusgraph/docs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://moolen.github.io/statusgraph/docs/configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://moolen.github.io/statusgraph/docs/configuration/</guid>
      <description>Configuration This section is a reference for the command-line interface, usage of environment variable and config.yaml file. Statusgraph has a simple client-server architecture. The Server serves the SPA Frontend, stores the graph data on disk and proxies metrics request to prometheus.
CLI The server serves the Webapp and is the API Server that stores the graph information and issues requests towards prometheus/alertmanager.
Usage: statusgraph server [flags] Flags: --config string path to the config file which contains the server configuration (default &amp;quot;/etc/statusgraph/config.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://moolen.github.io/statusgraph/docs/getting_started/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://moolen.github.io/statusgraph/docs/getting_started/</guid>
      <description>Getting Started What is Statusgraph? Statusgraph is the status page for your distributed system. It lets you visualize components and dependencies of your system and indicates their status.
Conceptually, you want to know if your service is &amp;ldquo;running&amp;rdquo;, i.e. it is in a binary state: red lamp vs. green lamp. This question is incredibly hard to answer. Statusgraph takes this approach:
 define alerts in Prometheus. They tell us when a services is considered in a &amp;ldquo;red&amp;rdquo; state (service is dead / not available / has issues .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://moolen.github.io/statusgraph/docs/usage/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://moolen.github.io/statusgraph/docs/usage/</guid>
      <description>Usage examples Tutorial use-case: colorizing the nodes Let&amp;rsquo;s take a look at the following very simple graph:
[frontend] --&amp;gt; [backend] Both services expose a metric http_request_latency_seconds:mean5m with labels app=frontend and app=backend.
And let&amp;rsquo;s consider the following Alert rule as an real life™ example.
groups: - name: Backend rules: - alert: HighRequestLatency expr: http_request_latency_seconds:mean5m{app=&amp;#34;backend&amp;#34;} &amp;gt; 0.5 for: 10m labels: severity: critical # &amp;lt;--- we only want to display alerts with severity=critical service_id: backend # &amp;lt;--- this is a node in our graph annotations: summary: High request latency The following mapping does this:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>